这一生犹如造物主奇异的杰作
How strange a work of providence is the life of man
这些年我流落荒岛摆脱困境已属无望
All my years upon this desolate island
摆脱困境已属无望
void of all hope of recovery
唯我独生船上同伴皆葬身海底
But I am alive and not drowned as all my ship's company was
我是鲁宾逊·克鲁索
I am Robinson Crusoe
放眼望去我如同身陷囹圄
Wherever about my prison I may look
但心中却仍是那片失落的乐园
In my mind's eye is the paradise I lost
我唯一的解脱是沉醉于回忆
My only escape is into the memory of a life
那似乎永远像个消逝的梦想
which seems ever more like a fading dream
我准备着那天的来临
This day finds me prepared
我对世界从未放弃过希望
I have never given upon the world
我相信上帝还未弃我而去
and I have faith that providence has not yet given up on me
一艘船
A ship
英国国旗
An English flag
Dundee 快来
Dundee come on
欢迎来到天堂
Welcome to paradise
大家自便
Make yourselves comfortable
嗨
Hey
那是什么
What's that
Judy 我们给你物色了一名夫婿
Hey Judy we found you a husband
臭哄哄的船难者想泡我的机会
A stinking castaway has got about as much chance as the rest of you
你认为是船难者
Castaway you reckon
假如他知道黄金呢
What if he knows about the gold
这里
Hey Here
我手无寸铁
I'm unarmed
别浪费弹药 距离太远了
Ah don't waste your powder not at this distance
去 抓住他
Go get him
我们去抓住他
Ah you lubber Let's get him
留下几个
Eli stay here
我们遇到了一个狡猾的家伙
We've a crafty one here then
我在这发现一个死人
Well I've got a dead one here
我们不能就这样罢手离开
Now we can't just leave it can we
看这作了记号 所以对他的陷阱了如指掌
Look at this He's blazed a trail so he'll know his own traps
如果你看到类似的记号 要务必小心
If you see another mark like this watch out
一 二 三 四 五 六
One two three four five six
嗨
Hey hey
在地狱里再待一会儿
Stuck in hell a little while longer
地狱或是男人该经历的地方
Hell is wherever a man happens to be
这会让他远离所爱之事与物
If it keeps him from what he loves
星期五想知道陷阱是哪种白痴制造
Friday wonders what kind of idiot builds all those traps
然后跑啊叫啊 手无寸铁地到海滩上去
then runs yelling to the beach without a weapon
你知道我去了海滩了
You knew I was at the beach
看到烽火我就猜到了
I could guess it from the beacons
既然那样的话
Well in that case crusoe wonders
为何知道星期五 不快速加入呢
why Friday didn'tjoin in sooner
我在欣赏白痴好戏呢
I was enjoying the idiot show
你会选择开枪 还是把他们打倒
Do you shoot those or bring them down
或是更加聪明的办法
with a well aimed shot of wit
弹无虚发
One bird one arrow
我知道 你是个天生的射手
I know One of nature's marksmen
这里有个天生的猎物
Says one of nature's targets
这里没人说英语吗
Hey hey does any one here speak English
我是英国人
I am English
那为何你用西班牙语咒骂
Then why do you curse in Spanish
在西班牙帆船上干了六年
Six years below decks  on a Spanish galleon
没什么事情可做
There's not much else to do
我对你不构成威胁但你却朝我开枪 为什么
I wasn't a threat to you but you fired on me Why
我什么都不会说的
Do your worst I'll say nothing
那看起来很痛啊
That looks painful
是啊
It is
但不致命 我将它拔出来吧
But not mortal I will pull it through
我招 什么都招
I'll talk I'll tell you everything
这里这小岛上有探险家的黄金
There's There's a conquistador gold on the island
我们有地图林奇(Lynch)认为你也在找那个
We got a map Lynch thought you might be after it too
谁是Lynch 你们老大
Who's Lynch your leader
我们中没有老大
We don't have a leader
2死1伤
Two men dead one wounded
他安全回到海滩上
and he's back safe on the beach
依我看他就是老大
That sounds like a leader to me
你的船在哪
Where's your ship
没有大船只有我们来的那个单桅帆船
No ship just thesloop we came in
谢谢你
Thank you
不幸的是
Unfortunately
星期五需要他的箭
Friday still needs his arrow
星期五也可以穿外套
Friday could use a coat
这位先生 很可惜不再需要外套了
This gentleman alas needs a coat no longer
为什么他说话方式那么奇怪
Why doe she talk like that
星期五需要这个星期五说过那个
"Friday needs this Friday says that"
他在取笑我 他知道我不能叫出他的真名
He's making fun of me He knows I can't pronounce his real name
- 你应该揍他  -是啊 我会试试的
- You should beat him  - Yeah I'll try that
为什么叫星期五呢
But why Friday
我在星期五找到他的
The day of the week I found him
于是想把他训练成仆人
I had this idea I was going to train him as a servant
至于他为什么一直跟着我我也不明白
Why he stuck with me I don't know
你不能和野人做朋友
You can't make a friend of a savage
那野人能懂12种不同语言
That savage can make himself understood in 12 different languages
学会英语只用了6个月
It took him six months to learn mine
我给他读了失乐园现在他能给我背诵
I've read him Paradise Lost and now he recites it back at me
但他自己不会读 对吧
So he can't read for himself then eh
不会
No
是啊 野人
Yeah savages
哇
Ow
听着 2个人死了
Listen with two men dead
现在船上有空余位置
you'll have space on the boat now
你的脸皮真厚 一点不假
You've got a thick skin and no mistake
我的子女有危险
My children are in danger
我得回到英国去
and I need to get back to England
别和这些船员走很郑重的建议哦
Well not with this crew and that's serious advice
一旦找到黄金 人人安危难保
Soon as the gold's out the ground nobody's safe
短兵相接 没有后路可退你和你的星期五
Daggers drawn and don't turn your back you and your man Friday
我不想要你们的黄金
I don't want your gold
你去跟那些西班牙渣子说好了
Explain that to the scum of the Spanish Main
你会熬不过第一晚的
You'll not last the first night
那么我会这么做
Then here's what I'll do
没人会干扰你们的任务
No one will interfere with your mission
你将看不到我们
You won't even see us
但你得为我做件事
But do this one thing for me
当你回到陆地上
When you return to the mainland
告诉当权者这里有个岛
tell someone in authority that here is an island
小岛上有个落难已久的男人
and on it is a man who's desperate
迫切渴望回乡和心爱的人团聚
to get to his home and the ones he loves
你会那么做吗
Will you dot hat for me
这要求不算高吧
Surely that's not too much to ask
20多年来没人尊重过我
No one's showed me respect in more than 20 years
我 那个曾要开枪杀你的家伙
Me who tried to shoot you down
嗯
Mmm
我喜欢好故事
I love a good story
我还发现我需要熟悉小岛的人
I also find I'm in need of a man with some local knowledge
船长Lynch的手枪倒是不错
Those are some pretty fancy pistols our captain Lynch has there
说不定他下岸就射不准了
Maybe he's all show and cannot shoot straight
你逃跑试试看 我们就知道准不准了
You run for it we' ll soon find out
呃
Aye
有什么要说的一起分享下啊
If you've got something to say why doesn't you share it
你在海上做什么
What's your business in these waters
私掠船
Privateers
隶属圣乔治
under the flag of St George
- 他们是海盗  - 嗯
- They're pirates  - Hmm
我们更喜欢"寻宝人"这个称呼
Ah we prefer"gentlemen of fortune"
都没有一艘大船
With no ship
命运使然 天有不测风云
Aye thanks to the small dip in our fortune
大船在甘达海岸因事而破损
at the guns of the Guarda costa
我们送去修理了
which we're hereto remedy
快点 快 跟上
Hurry up Come on clear it
女士们 先生们 鲁宾逊·克鲁索
Lady and gentlemen Mr Robinson Crusoe
称这个小岛是监狱
calls this island a prison
不好意思
Sorry
你只要告诉我们怎么去目的地就行了
You just show us how to get to where we need to be
我可不知道你们要去哪
Well I don't know where you need to be
我们有地图
We have a map
谁做的
Who made this
看就够了吧
Just look will you
不行 很抱歉 我帮不了你
It's no good I'm sorry I can't help you
告诉克鲁索 他不帮忙的话 会有什么后果
Show Mr Crusoe what'll happen if he doesn't help
好吧 来吧
All right come on boy
等一下
Hold
太恐怖了
Strike me down
看起来解决掉一个了
Looks like that one sank
野人们怎样他们会游泳吗
How does it go with savages Do they swim
我可不是这么想的
That was not really what I had in mind
但我也跟你说清楚了吧
But is my point made
我们看地图吧 好吧
Let's just look at the map all right
看啊 这没有太多地标
See there's not many landmarks
是啊 老爷子
You Crimp
我告诉过你了
I told you the old man's mind was going
那老男人心智日衰没能完成地图
He never got to finish it
这有一条河但没有山
There's a river but there's no mountains
我也不知道这是啥
And I have no idea what this is
那是我的痣啦
That's me mole
那些字是什么
What about the writing
从杀人岩那
From the killing rocks
从接吻岩石那直到顶峰
From the kissing rocks
用鹰的眼睛
to the highest peak
看到深之最深处
and from the eagle's eye to the deepest deep
那是什么意思
Now what couldthat mean
我不知道
I have no idea
赶快走
Moving on
这是我的建议
Here's what I suggest
你只要带我们要去的地方即可
You just take us where we need to go
因为我们一得到想要的就会离开
'cause the sooner we get what we want
我可不能给你定心丸
the sooner we'll be gone
Well I can't promise any miracles
这个小岛上的许多地方我都没见过
See there's an awful lot of this island even I haven't seen
是啊 别指望搭我们的顺风船了
Yeah well forget any thought of leaving with us
这帮人不行
Not with this Crew
很多事比困在荒岛更糟
There are worse things than being marooned
你明白吗
Do you understand
桶里是啥啊
So what's in the barrels
炸药
Gunpowder
假如要把财宝从地下炸出来就会用到
in case we have to blast the treasure out of the ground
看起来很重啊
Looks heavy
是的
I suppose it is
跟我讲讲 带你来这个岛的船呢
So tell me this ship that brought you to the island
残骸在哪里
where's the wreck
别提了 暴风雨摧毁了它  什么东西也没留下
Forget it Storms broke it up There's nothing left you can plunder
真可怜
Ah pity
在这之后会怎么对待我
So what happens to me after this
我猜可能会有一些表达谢意的方式吧
I suppose we'll find some way to show our gratitude
带我去个友好的港口
Take me to a friendly port
或许吧
Maybe
算了 还是把我扔这吧
Forget it Just leave me alone
那是小意思
Well that's the least we can do
我们尽量帮你一些
And we do try to do the least we can
那么 你要带我们去哪
So where are you taking us
去我认识的岩石那
To some rocks I know
他们有几分像在接吻
They're sort of kissing
遗憾的是你得野重新物色个野人
Sorry about you'll have to get another
跟我讲讲这个地图吧
Well tell meabout this map
我爸爸做的
My father made it
他在哪
And where is he
死了
Dead
他是个小偷也是个海盗
He was a thief and a pirate
听起来你很为他骄傲啊
You sound very proud of that
除了这也没有可骄傲的了
He did nothing else to be proud of
我想你爸是个很正派的人吧
I expect yours was a decent man
是的 如果他还活着的话
And still is If he lives
父亲啊 无论你还活着还是死去
Our father whether you live or you die
你永远都在我身旁
you are never far away from me
现在你必须很勇敢了 小Robin
You must be brave now young Robin
是啊 父亲
Yes Father
我也得这样
As must I
我们度过了很多美好的日子 对不对
We've had many a happy day have we not
当不幸的日子来临
And when an unhappy day comes along
我经常挂在嘴边的话是
what do I always say
我们必须从那些快乐时光中汲取力量
That we must draw strength from those better times
对的
That's right
为什么Blackthorn先生来这
Why is Mr Blackthorn here
他是我们的好朋友
He's been a good friend to us
今天我感觉需要一个朋友
and today I fear I will need one
你永远有我啊
You've always got me
是的 Robin
Yes Robin
我一直都有你
I will always have you
你进去过了吗
Have you been inside
没 还没有
No not yet
James 我想Robin该呆在外面
James I think Robin ought to stay out here
有因即有果
As to the events that led to
使我沦落于此荒岛的种种事件
My circumstance on the island
今日想来 便是始于 那一天
I now believe that they began on that day
接吻石
Kissing rocks
觉得如何
What do you think
现在怎样
Now what
从接吻岩石那直到顶峰
Well from the kissing rocks to the highest peak
这岛上最高的山是哪座
What's the highest mountain on this island
那就应该是我们从这里看到的最高的山
Well that's got to be the highest mountain that we can see from here
对
Yeah
觉得不对就纠正我
Correct me if I'm wrong
不过我觉得应该是那边那座
but I'd say it's that one right there
别看着我 不是我写的
Well don't look at me I didn't write it
唉
Oi
快追 你这个懒鬼 快呀
Well get after him you lazy sods Move
是我的话会更小心的
Ah I would be more careful
你知道这玩意会伤人的
You should see the damage one of those could do
我以为你知道呢
I take it you have
拜托 我们不能我们不能谈谈吗
Please can we can we just talk about this
谈什么呢我警告过你别跑
What's to talk about I warned you not to run
给他支剑
Somebody give him a sword
请别逼我和个女人斗
Please don't make me fight a woman
给她一顿痛扁 Crusoe
Give her a good old drubbing Crusoe
就当是我的私人请求
I'd consider that a personal favor
我要警告你 在我的家乡
I should warn you where I come from
剑被看作是每个年轻绅士的武器
the sword is considered the weapon of every young gentleman
在我的家乡 我们不像年轻绅士那样打斗
Where I come from we don't fight like young gentlemen
这样吧 如果你打败了Judy
I tell you what if you get past Judy
怎样 你会我猜猜 你会放我走
What You’ll Let me guess you'll let me go
我不相信你
I don't believe you
100码起步 有额外奖励给抓到你的那个人
A 100-yard start with an extra share for the man that catches ya
也就是我
and that'll be me
不 我们停下来吧
No Let's stop this eh
怎么了 Crusoe先生
What's the matter Mr Crusoe
我以为这是个值得一搏的机会
I thought that's a sporting Chance
如果他没有打败我 额外奖励就是我的了
If he doesn't get past me the extra share is mine
停下
Stop this
你能把它从我手上击落吗
Can you knock it out of my hand
能吗
Can you
加油 Judy
Come on Judy
加油啊
Come on
别急 Judy 别急
Easy Judy easy
有人落水了
Man overboard
这是干什么
What was that for
永远别帮我
Never help me
你应该谢谢他
You should thank him
为什么
What for
她本要杀了你的
She'd have killed you
不 我不这么认为
No I don't think so
金子还是没有金子
Gold or no gold
你看看她那时候的脸 那是死神的脸
when you see that face on her that's the face of death that is
我见过死神的脸
I have seen the face of death
当我还是孩童之时 生活充满战火和瘟疫
When I was a child we lived through fire and plague
但从来没有任何的苦难
But no trial I have ever faced then or now
有如我父亲那一天所经历的那样艰难
was as hard as the one my father had to face that day
很多
So many
溺死河中的人都被带到这里
Anyone who drowns in the river they bring them here
贫民 孤儿 自杀者
Paupers orphans suicides
许多无人认领
Do many go unclaimed
大部分 估计是
Most of them I imagine
女性30岁或以上眼球棕色
Woman 30 years or more
浅肤色浅发色
eyes colored brown fair of skin and hair
发现于莱姆豪斯河段
washed up at Limehouse Reach
哦 上帝啊
Oh dear Lord
这个吗
Why this
勇敢点 James
Courage James
她告诉我她很幸福
She told me she was happy
我不知道对孩童来说哪个更难以接受
I don't know what's harder for a child
母亲的死亡还是父亲的哭泣
to see your mother dead or your father cry
那些可能有毒的
Those may not be safe to eat
我在西班牙的监狱里呆了16年
I've been 16 years in a Spanish prison
我什么都能吃
I can eat anything
16年
Sixteen years
直到这群人出现 把我弄了出来
Till this bunch showed up busted me out
他们想要的倒不是我
It wasn't me they wanted
是这张地图 将其聚到了一起
It was this map she put 'em up to it
她说是她父亲画了这幅地图
She said her father drew the map
在一个满是煤烟和生锈的钉子的臭烘烘的地牢里
In that stinking dungeon with soot and a rusty nail
- 天啊  -是的
- Ouch  -Yeah
他知道自己不行了 而他的秘密将消失
He knew his mind was going and his secret with him
他花了两年时间
It took him two years
一天天变得疯狂
getting madder every day
所以在他完成小岛地图之前
So before he could finish mapping the island
他意识不清了
His mind went
他忘了我的名字
He forgot my name he forgot his own
忘了自己的名字 又过了一年他才死去
It took him another year to die
她几乎不认识他
She barely knew him
但是他们说她很难过
But they say she took it hard
他不奇怪吗
Isn't he strange
自从他妈妈淹死以后 他一个字都没说过
He hasn't said a word since the day his mother drowned
我不认为他奇怪
I don't think he's strange
你不能让他开口的 我们都试过了
You'll not get him to speak We've all tried
你好 你好
Hello hello
看看当你示好的时候得到了什么
See what you get when you try to be friendly
他叫什么名字
What's his name
听起来有点外国的那种
It's one of those foreign-sounding ones
Krutznower
你叫Crusoe 不是吗
It's Crusoe isn't it
我听说你爸爸把名字改了
I heard that your father changed it
但已经不能把它刻在墓碑上了
but it was too late to put it on the stone
你叫Robinson Crusoe
You're Robinson Crusoe
我叫Susannah
My name's Susannah
我妈妈也死了
My mother died too
不会是那种玩意儿吧
Is that what I think it is
不是 如果你觉得闻到了玫瑰香
Not if you think you can smell roses
我会回到你身边的 Susannah
Susannah I will return to you Susannah
不管他们怎么说 相信我 我会回去的
Whatever they may tell you believe that I will
告诉我 Crusoe先生
So tell me Mr Crusoe
岛屿的统治者
ye governor of all the island
我们已经从"接吻岩"到了"最高峰"
we've been from kissing rocks to highest peak
不错
Lovely
那么"鹰眼"和"深之最深处"又如何呢
How about eagle's eye and deepest deep now eh
你不是要我去吧 是吗
You're not going to let me go are you
你不知道
You don't know that
你一找到了金子 就会杀了我的
Once you find the gold you're going to kill me
没那个必要
Not necessarily
就是说我要相信突然的暴富
So I should believe that
会使你的仁慈之心大爆发
sudden riches will give you a burst in generosity
更奇怪的事情也发生过 我的朋友
Stranger things have been known to happen my friend
那一定是你的鹰眼
That's got to be your eagle's eye
确实是
So it is
"鹰眼"
Oi eagle's eye
你的伤怎么样了 Tibbets
How's that wound Tibbetts you up to carrying on
准备好坚持了吗
You'll have to leave me
我得让你来留下了
I'll only slow you down
继续前进
Moving on
你在找什么
What are you looking for
守护天使
A guardian angel
听我一句 没这么个东西
Take it from me there's no such thing
那取决于谁在盯着你
That depends who's watching out for you
现在怎么办
Now what
你们呆在这 我看看水有多深
Well you stay here I'll see how deep it gets
你到了对岸
Ah You get to the other side
就不在火枪射程内了
then you're gonna be out of musket range
我不这么想
I don't think so
你 来做
You Do it
为什么是我
Why me
因为你最臭
'cause you smell the worst
去吧
Get on with it
去吧 臭蛋
Yeah go on smelly
我告诉过他别吃浆果
I told him not to eat the berries
我觉得这是最深的地方了
I think this is about as deep as it gets
走完再确定
Go all the way to be sure
Crusoe先生 你是个会变通的小伙子
Mr Crusoe you being an adaptable fella
怎么保持我们的火药干燥 有建议吗
any suggestions as to how we can go about keeping our powder dry
有东西咬我
Something bit me
咬回来
Well bite it back
坚持
Carry on
河里有什么啊
What's in the river
我流血了
I'm bleeding
可能是那个
There may be something
- 蛇  -不是 没有蛇
- Snakes  -No No snakes
除非食人鱼漏掉了一条
Not unless the piranhas missed one
你觉得这很有趣
Ye think that's funny
我觉得
I do
路途才过半 我们就损失了四个人
Half a day on this island and four men gone
我该感到震惊吗
Am I supposed to be impressed
- 我震惊了  -你能闭嘴吗
- I am  - Will you shut up
你认为我不会杀了你 因为我需要你
Now you think I won't kill you because I need ya
那不会有什么意义 不是吗
Well that wouldn't make much sense would it
不会可你有两个眼睛
No but you got two eyes
像数手指头般玩弄 这有可能改变 我的朋友
and ten fingers and that may change my friend
听明白了吗
Am I understood
是的
Yes
现在
Now
我们到底该怎么过去
how do we really get across
你实在有太多闲工夫了 我的朋友
You've had far too much time on your hands my friend
这是没得选择的
It's not like it was out of Choice
哈
Hmm
下一个谁
Who goes next
我
I do
枪械该怎么处理
But what about the guns
你带上它们
You bring them
不能事事都我做吧
I can't manage everything by myself
那就往返两趟
Well make two trips
你个白痴
You idiot
那个Judy 她有点恐怖哦
That Judy she's a bit formidable
那你试试在监狱里出生
Well you should try being born in a prison
我是指真的监狱
And I mean a real one
不是你的幻想小岛
not your fancy island here
Leport 他幻想自己和她有机会
LaPorte he fancied his Chances with her
谁是Leport
Who's LaPorte
刚才被你喂鱼的那个
The one you just fed to the man-eating fish
非常感谢
thank you very much
我们丢了船的前一天晚上
The night before we lost the ship
他在她耳边说了点悄悄话
he whispered something in her ear
她一只手把他按在地上
She pinned himdown with one hand
另一只手差点把他的眼睛挖出来
Near ripped his eye out with the other
听起来好恐怖
That sounds grim
对他 是的
Well for him yeah
对我们剩下的人却非常有趣
It was very entertaining for the rest of us
我告诉你点事
I'll tell you something
我不会去做试图驯服她的男人
I wouldn't want to be the man who tries to tame her
快点 Bagwell
Hurry upBagwell
从接吻岩到最高峰
From the kissing rocks to the highest peak
鹰眼所望之深渊
and the eagle's eye to the deepest deep
这里 这里
Here Here
你不是个平凡的男人 Crusoe
You're an unusual man Crusoe
与什么相比
Compared to what
你也很会打斗
You fight well too
只在必须的时候
Only when I have to
更是个好情人
More of a lover eh
你有女人吗
You got a woman
我有妻子
I have a wife
当然了 她叫什么名字
Of course What's her name
Susannah 而她叫我
Susannah And she calls me
鲁宾逊
Robin
好了
All right
鲁宾逊
Robinson
出自韦斯特郡织工之手的蕾丝
Fine lace from west country weavers
做这些赚来的钱可以买匹马
With the money I make from this I can buy a horse
骑着它可以去买织布机
And with a horse I can ride out and buy straight from the loom
用我从中赚的钱
With the money I make from that
可以投入船运贸易中
I can buy an interest in a ship
五年后
And in five years' time
如果命运公平不出意外的话
if the fates play fair then you
你就能成Crusoe帝国的女主人了
Could be mistress to the empire of Crusoe
女主人
Mistress
你知道我想娶你的
You know what my intentions are
过来看看
Come and see this
怎么样
What do you think
做我们的第一个家不错吧
Good enough for our first home
Robin 你真是非同凡响
Oh Robin you're impossible
应该说是天才之极
Mmm I thought I was rather ingenious
嗯 好吧
Mmm All right
为了添置点家具 我想把婚礼延后
I'm willing to postpone the wedding for want of some proper furniture
还得找间房子
And a house to put it in
慢慢来吧
Steady on
如果我爸爸看到这些
If my father saw this
别说他会看低我
Don't say he'd think less of me
我想他会的
I don't think he could
如果他不让你嫁给我怎么办
What would I do if he ever took you away from me
可我只爱你一个
You know I've never loved anyone else
嗯
Mmm
你救了我的命
You saved my life
没有
I did not
没了我你可能不会那么幸福  但一定得活下去
You might not be so happy without me but I know you'd survive
鲁宾逊
Robin
箭无虚发
One bird one arrow
都趴下
Everybody down
- 嗨  - 抱歉
- Hey  - Sorry sir
野人 给我放下弓箭
Savage drop your bow
武器装备扔下悬崖
Throw your weaponsover the cliff
他不会说英语
He doesn't speak English
可我会说野人语
Yeah but I speak savage
快扔下去
Throw them over the cliff throw them now
快扔掉 不然封刀见血
Or you'll get to seethe color of Crusoe's blood
把弓箭扔下去
Throw your weapons over the cliff
快
Throw them now Now
走开
Now jump
我们看他掉下去的
We saw him fall
怎么没死
Why isn't he dead
没见他掉下去就看见他跳了
We didn't see him fall we only saw him jump
你差点害死我
You nearly killed me
他会跟着我们的
He's gonna keep on following us
这样他就跟不了了
Not if we do this
那怎么回到船上去
How do we get back to the boat
我相信天才·克鲁索 会有所发明的
I'm sure the ingenious Mr Crusoe will devise something for us
对吧 Robin
Won't you Robin
嘘
Shh
嗨
Oi
人活得真累啊
A man grows weary
我在西班牙从军了23年
I spent 23 years in the service of New Spain
到头来落到这下场
and look at the bunch of dogs I end up with
哦 别担心他们 没有一个是英国人
Oh don't worry about them not one of them English
也不会用其母语交涉有用信息
nor any useful conversationin their own language
我对你很好奇野人兄弟
You interest me savage
为何
Why
你说那个鲁宾逊·克鲁索时候 像在说自己兄弟
You speak of this Robinson Crusoe like he's a brother
那些海盗带着地图来的
Those pirates came herewith a purpose
如果你能保证Crusoe的安全
If you can guarantee me Crusoe's safety
我就告诉你他们要找什么
I will tell you what they're looking for
这岛上没金子的
Oh there's no gold on this island
30年前我们军队曾到访过
Our army went over it30 years ago
如果有 也是以前的事了
If there ever was any it's long gone
他们以为他会带路去找宝藏
Well they think he's guiding them to it
只有这样他才能保住
Then that's the only thing that's keeping him alive
我们得涉水过去了
I think we are aboutto get our feet wet
哦 不
Oh no
不 最好别涉水
Not the best of ideas
河里有很多寄生虫
The river is infested
你们得搭个木筏
Your men will have to build a raft
叫他们来搭木筏  有点天方夜谭
Build a raft These men they wouldn't know how
他是队中最出色的 可都能被椰子砸晕
That one came second in a fight with a coconut tree and he's the best of them
叫他们听我的 我会告诉他们怎么做
Order your men to obey me I will tell them what to do
如此甚好
This will be good
Crusoe先生 惊喜连连啊
So Mr Crusoe so full of surprises
这岛上还有其他人吗
Is there anyone else on this island
没了
Nobody
那野人呢 还有其他野人吗
What about your savage Anymore like him
他不是什么野人
He's not a savage
那是什么
Explain him then
他教我如何重新活下去
He's the man that taught me how to live again
呃 肯定是孤独透了吧
Ooh That must have been some powerful solitude
你们怎么认识的
How did you two meet
能休息下吗 就一会儿
Can we stop just for a minute Only a minute
累死可不值得
It's not worth skinning a person for
走
Let's go
如果要投票定你生死 不管是否值得 我会选择让你活着
For what it's worth if it came to a vote I'd let you live
就因为你前面差点打败了我
Just 'cause you nearly beat me in a fight
我这是示爱
Where I come from that counts as courtship
我说过我是有妇之夫
I told you I'm a married man
那打输是我的习惯了
Well then losing fights should be second nature
你真是在监狱里出生的
Is it true you were born in a prison
我倒希望是
I might as well have been
克鲁索先生
Mr Crusoe
别让他等着
Don't keep him waiting
这岛上有几条河
How many rivers are thereon this island
我是个漂流者 可不是调查者
I'm a cast a way not a surveyor
岛末端的河是由西往东流的
The last river was flowing from left to right
可这条这由东往西的
This one's flowing from right to left
这怎么解释
How do you explain that
是同一条河 就是中间有个大弯流
It's the same river with a very big bend in it
想听听另一种解释吗
You want to hear another explanation
假设向导先生在骗我们呢
Suppose our guide was deceiving us
假设他知道宝藏所在的位置
Suppose he worked out the actual location of the treasure
又要隐瞒不说 所以带着我们兜圈子呢
and was keeping it to himself while leading the rest of us
你不觉得我的解释更说得通吗
around in one big Circle
Don't you think my explanation's better
- 不  - 未必
- No  - I do
既然如此 那怎么解释太阳在那边
In that case can you explain to me why the sun is over there
按我这个老水手的经验看 应该在那边啊
when by this old sailor's reckoningit should be over there
因为你认错方向了
Because your reckoning is wrong
我已经受够了
I've had enough of this you know
我要马上杀了你
I think I'm gonna kill you right now
杀了我 就能证明你是个傻瓜
You go ahead and do that and I'll die knowing what a fool you are
来啊
Do it
我也受够了
I'm tired of you
不管我帮没帮到你们 你最后都会杀了我
You've no intention of letting me live whether I help you or not
你还不知道自己在哪吗
Can't you see where you are
朝周围看看
Look around you
我们正在鹰眼处 正中间
We're in the eagle's eye right in the middle of it
离这两英里处 这条河流向无底瀑布
And this river two miles from here it falls into a bottomless pool
深不见底
The deepest deep
杀了我
So shoot me
你就自己去找吧
and go and find it on your own
Crusoe先生
Mr Crusoe
请您帮忙带路好吗
would you kindly lead the way
好的
I will
要是谁能帮忙搬火药
If somebody else will kindly carry the powder
我爸爸一队人在去西班牙的路上掳获黄金
My father's Crew captured the gold on his way to Spain
然后铸成炮弹的形状投运回家
and they cast it in the shape of a cannon to smuggle it home
据说得到被抓捕的消息前 即将黄金掩埋
Legend has it that they buried it when they knew they'd be caught
并发誓不得泄露埋葬位置
and they all took a vow not to reveal where
但你爸爸还是泄露了
But your father broke it
是在其他队员死后说出来的
Not while the others were alive
统治者想用美人计骗他说出秘密
The Governor even sent a woman to romance the story out of him
所以我不是生在监狱里 是在那儿有了我
So you see I wasn't born ina prison I was just made in one
朱迪
Judy
钱啊 我们怎么办
Money eh What won't we do for it
钱财对我来说曾是个问题
Money was a problem for me once upon a time
Susannah的爸爸是伦敦最大的制桶商之一
Susannah's father owns one of London's largest cooperages
他一定会用丰厚的嫁妆给女儿陪嫁
A man like that won't let his daughter go without a substantial dowry
我不要他的钱
I don't want his money
很公平 给你的穷爸爸
Fair enough Pass it on to your poor old father
我要看着他的眼睛跟他说钱不是万能的
I want to be able to look him in the eyes and tell him that money never came into it
那样显得很高尚 Robinson
That's very noble Robinson
自尊心可不能当饭吃
But you can't feed a new family on your pride
我能跟Jeremiah谈谈你的事吗
If I speak to Jeremiah for you
无法想象Blackthorn先生出借房子
I can't imagine Mr Blackthorn having a room to rent
可以说是放贷
About a loan
我不大熟悉他
I barely know him
他对你一直很上心
He's always take nan interest in you
你妈妈死后 他还想领养你
When your mother died he wanted to adopt you
你认为他现在会选择我吗
You think he'dad opt me now
让我们严格地谈生意 好吗
Let's keep it strictly business shall we
从鹰眼到深之最深处
From the eagle's eye to the deepest deep
野人星期五
According to Friday the savage
曾说过这瀑布深不见底
the pool at the end of this waterfall has no bottom
那么
And
继续什么
And what
那么金制炮弹到底在哪
And so where be the golden cannon
往后看
Look behind you
Hmm
嗯
跟上他
Get after him
我很乐意
Love to
你先请
You first
又来了
Oh calamity
你没事吧
Are you all right
放轻松
Easy Easy
好
All right
上面是谁
Who's up there
西班牙狱卒
Spanish prison guards
什么
What guards
我带他们一路走来
I brought them across the piranha river
来得正是时候
And no complaints about my timing eh
兄弟 谢谢你
Hey hey my brother thank you
别客气
My pleasure
走吧
Let's go
她长得真迷人
She's a very striking-looking woman
我也觉得
Can't say I noticed
再等她就走了
Any longer and she would have been all over you
这就是克鲁索效应
It's the Crusoe effect
我心中只有一个女人
You know there's only one woman in my life
你现在可以回到她身边去了
And now you can go back to her
他们要走了
Hey they are leaving the island
我知道
I know
他们不是狱卒 他们是西班牙的海岸卫队
Those aren't prison guards that's the Spanish Guarda Costa
英国海军都是他们的敌人
They hunt down English mariners and lock them up
不到万不得已都别想依靠他们
They're the last people I can surrender to
噢
Oh
如果要在他们和这个岛之间选一个
If it's a Choice of them or this island
我想我们还需要在岛上呆久一点
well I guess we gotta stay here a little while longer
终于传来一声柔和而庄重的呼吸声
At last a soft and solemn breathing sound
有如浓郁的蒸馏香水的蒸汽般升起
rose like a steam of rich distilled perfumes
飘散在空气中 在她意识到之前
and stole upon the air that even silence was took ere she was ware
希望她能改变自己的本性
and wished she might deny her nature
“再也不会像现在这样流离失所了
and be never more still to be so displaced
我洗耳恭听
I was all ear
也许死亡之肋骨可以创造出这样一个灵魂
and took in strains that might create a soul under the ribs of death
对不起 Crusoe
I am sorry Crusoe
为什么道歉
For what
让你失望了
Your disappointment
还会有其他船经过
Well there'll be other ships
我们还有机会
And other Chances
我应该给你说明那些陷阱的
I should explain about the man traps
你不需要这么做
You don't need to No
你应该问我 哪个笨蛋会设下这么多的陷阱
You asked me what sort of an idiot
然后却连武器也没带就跑到海滩上去
sets traps for invaders then goes running down to the beach without a weapon
那些陷阱都是你早设好的
Those traps were not made for your kind Crusoe
为了防止我逃跑
They were for mine
不是那样 拜托 Crusoe
That's not true Oh Crusoe come on
你看到了英国国旗
You saw the English flag
你就从来没有想过自己的同胞也可能会伤害你吗
You never thought for once you might have anything to fear from your own
我应该想到这点的
I should have known better
你现在终于明白了
You know better now
人就是这样的
Men are just men
相信我
Trust me
还有你的狗
Trust your dog
不要相信其他人
But trust no one else
不是每个人都会这样的
Everyone is not the same
不 我们都是一样的 我的兄弟
Yes we are my brother
我们会吃敌人的肉
My people eat the flesh of their enemies
而你们会饮上帝的血
while your people drink the blood of their god
你希望找到回家的路 我也想
You miss your people miss mine
你想念你的家人我也想我的家人
You wish you could find your way home so do I
唯一的区别就是我再也没有机会了
But the difference between us is that I know I never will
什么意思
What do you mean
Crusoe你做梦都想回家 是吧
Crusoe you dream about going home yes
对 但是我不能回去
Yes but I can't
你救了我
You saved my life
现在我的命就是你的了
And now I've pledged it to you
我会一直跟随你左右
Where you go I go
我从来没这么想过
Well that was never the idea
该怎么说才对 我释放你了
What do I have to say I release you
释放我
Release me
你不能释放我
You cannot release me
我不是你的奴隶
I am not your slave
对不起
I'm sorry
恨不得那是我的头吧
Is that instead of my head
严格来说 你还是食人族吧
Technically speaking you are still a cannibal right
自从我们养羊之后我就再也没碰过人肉了
As long as there are goats on the island I will never again taste human flesh
嗯 很高兴你变了
Well that's good to know
那如果羊都死光了呢
What if the goats die
那么
Then
你可千万别睡着了
Do not fall asleep
你的孩子会再见到他们父亲的
Your Children they will see their father again
我也深信这一点
I'm sure you're right
他们也会见到星期五叔叔
And on that day they will meet their uncle Friday
在那时 我就知道还有人在守护这他们
Well until that day I know that someone watches over them
你们的神
Your god
他们的教父
Their godfather
你以前都叫我叔叔的
You used to call me uncle
是吗
Did I
对不起 忘了你已经不是个孩子了
Oh I'm sorry I was forgetting you're not a Child anymore
没关系 我很快就要结婚啦
No sir I'm soon to be married
我知道 恭喜 你父亲告诉我 你需要一笔钱
Yes congratulations And your father tells me you need a loan
是 不过我没想过这么快就直接跟你说这个事情
Yes sir although I hadn't planned to bring us quite so quickly to the point
Robin 生命这么短暂
Well life is short Robin
拐弯抹角就是在浪费生命
and time spent dancing around a subject is time wasted
你需要多少钱
How much do you need a thousand
一千就够了
A thousand would be
我给你写张字条
I'll draw up a draft
我会还给你的
Well I will repay you
你给得出利息吗
Can you afford the Charge
那要看利息有多高了
That depends on what the Charge is
我一直想成为你的教父
I've always wanted to be a godfather
真的吗
Really
我排行第二 本来是无权继承的
Now I was a second son without prospect of a fortune
但因我哥哥过世 才得到这一切
Then my brother died and everything passed to me
但是如果我死了
But when I die
你会有自己的继承人的
There's time yet for a son of your own
对单身汉来说太难了
Oh difficult task for a bachelor
我听闻坊言有个男人付钱让女人给其生娃
I heard a story once of a man who paid a woman to bear him a Child
不过那也只是个故事罢了
But it was just a story
Dundee回来了
Dundee's back
星期五
Friday
终于找到他了
We found them
他们为什么找到这里来
Why are they here
我想他们是猜我知道宝藏在哪里
They think I know where the gold is
你真的知道
Do you
Crusoe先生
Mr Crusoe
他们举了个旗子
They've got a rag on a stick
很好 白色的
Yeah Is it a white one
嗯 差不多
Uh More or less
那是休战旗 先别开枪
Yeah it's the flag of truce Don't shoot first
至今七年霉运不断
It's seven years bad luck or something
不出来我要打死你的狗了
In your place Mr Crusoe I'll be shooting the dog
别以为我没有考虑
Don't imagine I'm not considering it
我给Santanathe上尉看了纹身藏宝图
I showed captain Santana the tattoo
发现我们其实有很多的共通点
now we find we have more in common than we thought
虽然立场不同 利益是一致的
Different sides same game
分成还是不一样的
You know different levels of rewards
Santana上校和我达成了协议
So captain Santana and me
我们目前有共同的兴趣
we've uh merged our interests
现在需要你告诉我们宝藏的地点
All we need now is for you to tell us where to find our gold
为什么你觉得我会知道
What makes you so sure I know
别在我面前说谎话 Crusoe先生 我可是说了一辈子的谎话
Don't try to lie to me Mr Crusoe I have been a liar all me life
告诉你们宝藏的地点
Say I can give you what you want
我们会有什么下场呢
What happens to us then
难说
I don't know
你有什么要求
What would you believe
尽管提
Make us an offer
离开这个岛
Get off my island
就这么简单
That's it
我要杀了那个野人 然后放了你 相信我
I'll kill the savage and I'll take you alive and then believe me
到时你说什么都可以
you will talk
他们都是军人
These boys are the sons of the Inquisition
我相信他们
I'd be inclined to believe him
谈判破裂 很抱歉
No deal Sorry
那么你是向我们宣战了
So it's war then
开战吧
It's war
我们要看住各个方向
We need to watch all sides
有什么问题吗
What
- 你知道宝藏在哪里  - 大概吧
- You know where the gold is  - Maybe
- Crusoe  -你要我怎么做
- Crusoe  - What if I do
告诉他们 让他们找到宝藏然后离开
Then tell them Let them take it and go
一旦他们找到宝藏我们就完蛋了
Once they get the gold we die
他们现在是这么说
They say that now
但只要找到宝藏他们必定内讧
but once they have got it they will not stick around and fight
我也希望会是那样 听着
I wish it were that simple Look
从亲吻石到最高点
From the kissing rocks to the highest peak
从鹰眼滩到最深处
from the eagle's eye to the deepest deep
我们就在宝藏上面
We're on top of it
我们不能坐着等死 得想个办法
We can't just sit tight We're in the way
他们藏在树后面
They're in the trees
他们上桥了
And on the bridge
克鲁索
Crusoe
怎么了
What's happening
他们想把我们熏下去
They're trying to smoke us out
只好用喝的水了
The drinking water
理智点吧 Crusoe先生 我们也想给你留个活口
See sense Mr Crusoe We'd rather have you in one piece
你死了就什么用处都没有了
You're of no use to anyone dead
一旦点燃 很快就会爆炸的
When this goes it'll go fast
我已经准备好了
I am ready
比我想象的还快
That was a bit faster than I expected
火药都湿了
My powder's wet
我去取点过来
I will get some more
星期五别去
No Friday
他回来了
He's back
这显然不是个好主意
Definitely not the best of ideas
他们的火药用完了 搬个火药桶过来
They're out of gunpowder get a keg
你知道该怎么做吧
You See
别让他们从桥上走过去
No let them walkover bridge
那边
There
取不到火药
I can not reach the powder
把他们炸出来
We'll blow them down
放到树下面去
Set it at the base of the tree
那艘船的名字叫“金色虚荣”
And the name of the ship was the Golden Vanity
我们担心她会被西班牙敌人袭击
And we feared she would be taken by the Spanish enemy
当她在低地航行时
As she sailed upon the lowland
低地低地
Lowland lowland
在低地航行
Sail upon the lowland
他们一定是在想办法
They're planning something
没错
Yes they are
别紧张 只有我一个人
Stand easy I'm alone
她能找到办法上来其他人也肯定可以
If she could find a way inhere the rest of them can
我可不这么想 她跟他们不是一个等级
I wouldn't guarantee that This one's a ship of a different Class
是Lynch让你过来的吗
Did Lynch send you
不是 他没然我过来
No sir he did not
我是自己过来的
I'm here of my own account
改变你的立场
To Change your colors
支持处于劣势的一方
To the losing side
我们认识的时间不长 Crusoe先生不过我想你还是了解我的
You haven't known me long Mr Crusoe but I think you know me better than that
然后
What then
我不喜欢看到一个好人无故死去
I hate to see a good man die for nothing
放弃宝藏 我能保证你的活路
Give up the gold and I'll make sure you live
那肯定不会是Lynch的主意
That's definitely not what Lynch has in mind
要改变一个人的想法枪是最有效的
Nothing Clears the mind like a musket ball passing through it
放弃吧 Crusoe
Oh come on Crusoe
你活不过明天早上的
You won't last the morning there are only two of you
你们只有两个人而且没有了火药
And you can't even reach your powder
你是打算要抗争到底了
You're going to fight
恐怕也只能这样了
I'm afraid so
真可惜 很公平
Pity It's a fair offer
是 不过我们的公平明显是不一样的
Hmm Yes but you and I we have different ideas of what fair is
但谢谢你的好心劝告
But thank you for the"good man" business
我告诉你我会怎么做吧
I'll tell you what I'll do
到时候我会杀了你们俩 迅速解决掉
When the time comes I'll kill you both myself and I'll make it quick
你真好心
Very kind
相信我
Oh trust me
有个西班牙人做了很坏的计划
one of those Spaniards has some very grim plans for you
啊 我能猜出是谁
Ah I can guess which one
我用椰子砸了他的头
I brained him with coconuts
伤他自尊了 干得好
Hmm Respecting his dignity Good for you
那再见了 Crusoe先生
Well then goodbye Mr Crusoe
晚安
Good night
朱迪思·朱迪
Judith·Judy
早上见
I'll see you in the morning
低地低地
lowland lowland
在低地海上航行
Sailed upon the lowland sea
然后船舱男孩开口说话了
Then up spoke the cabin boy
他无拘无束的畅说
And boldly out spoke he
你看上去挺高兴啊
You seem very happy
我已经在找乐子了 虽然不知道要从那开始
Ah I'm spending me gold already though I hardly know where to start
推荐你先去学唱歌吧
May I suggest singing lessons
作为一个即将暴富的穷大兵
For a dirt poor soldier who's suddenly gained some prospects
你看上去不怎么高兴啊
you don't seem very Cheerful
你还没拿出证据 说明Crusoe能找到宝藏
You have given me no proof that Mr Crusoe can show us the gold
不过事已至此 搭档
And yet here we are partner
我们不是搭档
We are not partners
你什么意思
What do you mean by that
你要明白这一点 没金子 就没自由
You need to understand something no gold no freedom
你不能事后把我们关进监狱
You can't drag us back to jail after this
今天下午 我两个手下死了
I lost two men this afternoon
你不在乎他们生死
You despise your men
没错 也许如此
Oh yes that might be so
但他们都身为人子
but every one of them is a mother's son
如果死了 我总要表示一下
If I send a man to die I need something to show for it
你会拿到抚恤金的
You'll get your prize
无论如何 我会的
One way or another yes I will
最好找到黄金 Lynch
Produce your gold Mr Lynch
否则明天 将再度成为你的西班牙敌人
or by this time tomorrow I'll be once again your "Spanish enemy"
你去哪了
Where have you been
英国人是不会问的
An English man wouldn't ask
真的吗
Really
我保证我们都能会逃出去的
I promise you we'll get out of this all right Both of us
我知道
I know
西班牙船长说 黄金大炮是个传说
The Spanish captain said the golden cannon is a legend
是真的吗
You don't say
如果自己都不相信 为什么要冒死追寻呢
If you don't even believe a thing exists why risk your life for it
他们没你看得淡
That's gold for you
他们来了 快走
Here they come Go Go
- 那是什么  -靠 是投石机
- What is that  -Oh it's a trebuchet
什么玩意
A what
一种大型弹弓
A type of catapult
你应该逃走
You should go
我来吸引他们 你顺着绳子下去 然后逃走
I'II   I'll distract them You climb down a rope and go
然后呢
Uh-huh Then what
我不知道 我会想出办法的
I don't know I'll work something out
他们会杀了你的 Crusoe
They will kill you Crusoe
也许不会
Well maybe not
也许暂时不会 但你也说了
Maybe not right away
如果发现岛上有黄金 他们就会杀了你
but you said it yourself if there's gold on this island they will kill you
如果没找到他们会慢慢折磨你 以免你隐瞒
If there's no gold they will kill you slowly in case you're holding back
无论如何 他们都没必要追杀你啊
Either way there's no need for them to come after you
别想了 Crusoe 拜托
Ah forget it Crusoe Come on
跟我来
Come with me
没事的
It's all right
我叫克鲁索 鲁宾逊·克鲁索
I'm Crusoe Robinson Crusoe
不不不
No no No no no
你叫
You You are
星期五
Friday
什么
What
没 没事
No nothing Nothing
拉
Pull
他们开始攻击我们了
They're sighting in on us
举起来快点
Heave high Come on
看上去不妙
That looks bad
非常不妙
Very bad
看似如此
Yeah Okay
准备好了吗
Ready
火药怎么样了
How's the powder
应该干了
It might be dry by now
还是很潮
Still damp
我们需要干燥的火药粒
We need some dry grains
- 那还要一会  -不行
- Well it will take a while before  - No
为何
Why
因为我们马上就要被炸下去了
Because we're about to get blown out of the tree
我来做 你看好他们
I'll do this you watch them
准备发射
Ready Ready
你在干什么
What are you doing
我要在火药桶投过来之前 引爆它
I need to blow the keg before it gets here
趴下
Get down
这个提前爆炸了
It exploded too soon
第二发就差不多了
They'll have us with the next one
没管用啊 Lynch
It is not working Mr Lynch
引线加长两英寸就能搞定了
Two more inches of fuse and that gentlemen will finish the job
拉回来 伙计们
Bring it back boys
那边抬起来
That's it
我要些火热的东西 引爆炸药
I need something red hot to set off the powder
用步枪子弹呢
Uh Not a musket ball
不行 步枪子弹是用铅做的 会融化的
No a musket ball is made from lead It'll melt
链珠呢
Beads
不行
No no
- 水桶呢  - 不行
- Pearls  - No
快点快点
Come on Come on
我需要金属 金属的东西
I need something metal anything metal
好的 你盯住他们 准备好的时候告诉我
Okay You watch them Tell me when they're ready to go
好的
Okay
举起来 抓紧时间填装
Heave Go get it on Get it on
他们装弹了
They're loading the keg
炸药桶装好了
The keg is loaded
快点
Come on
点燃引线了
Let's go Put on the fuse
引线点着了
Lighting the fuse
引线
The fuse is lit
不不
Oh no no no
继续烧
Trying again
Crusoe 来了
Crusoe it's coming
轻而易举啊 炸出来的洞
That's handy It's blown a hole to bury them in
够埋他们的了
Strike me down
杀了我吧
Will you look at that
你看看
We're rich
我们发财了
Well I cannot say your gold impresses me much
这些金子对我来说算不上什么
What's there could buy us a whole fleet of ships
这够买一支舰队了 乌木甲板 丝绸风帆
with ebony decks and silken sails
好吧 他们驶来之后 记得通知我
Fine Let me know when they get here
等等
Wait
这就说明 有艘空船了
This should mean there's a boat going spare
那你最好快点
Well you better be quick
为什么
Why
你点点人数 还有人活着
Count the bodies Not everyone is here
站住 除非你想入伙
Stop Unless you wish to join your countrymen
我不是来跟你争斗的
We're not hereto fight you
他放弃宝藏了
He's given upon the gold
我可不愿意丧身于此
I'm not prepared to die for a legend
他要送你入狱了
So he's taking you to prison
克鲁索效应
The Crusoe effect
往后站
Stand back
祝你好运
I wish you better
你也是 Crusoe
You do Crusoe
我可以杀了你 Crusoe
I could kill you Crusoe
我可以杀了你们俩
I could kill you both
这就意味着 你现在该离开
But knowing what it would mean for you to leave
我想者会让我更加开心
it will entertain me more to remember
把你留在鸟不拉屎的地方
where I left you to rot
别动
Stay
克鲁索
Crusoe
Dundee回来了
Dundee's back
嘿 到这里来
Hey come here come here Come on
这里 快点
Hey hey
金子怎么办
What about the gold
埋起来
Bury it
Why为什么
Why
它被诅咒了
It's Cursed
那埋起来是不管用的
Then burying it will not help
我的财富在远方 我的目标已明朗
My fortune lies elsewhere and my purpose is clear
一个男人矗立在孤岛上
Here there is an island and on it is a man who is sick with desire
他只想重返家乡 回到爱人身旁
to return to his home and the ones that he loves